# **Andy Chen**

Rich experience in full-stack software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team. Current hold AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate and Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) by Linux Foundation.

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

#### **EXPERIENCE**

<u>Minted LLC</u>, San Francisco — *Senior Infrastructure Engineer* March 2019 - PRESENT

- Improved internal tooling and speed up Jenkins continuous testing/deployment pipelines by at least 5 times.
- Author Kafka python/typescript client library
- Author internal protobuf development process from building, compiling, testing to deploying, distribution and migration, by leveraging GNU make, shell scripts and dockers.
- Maintain and build Kafka python client library, scale Flink/Beam data pipeline from one to N cluster each running K pipelines.

<u>New Internet Service Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Project Lead Developer* July 2018 - March 2019

- Leverage Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distribute stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decreased responding time by 50%.
- Develop a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

**Bodhi Project**, San Mateo— Senior Software Engineer May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Refactored the whole React UI library from redux to mobX architecture in 4 weeks and successfully initiated the migration from electron-based to browser-based DApp which ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2 times.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex solidity smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the development process.
- Built the prototype of ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Backend: **RESTful/GraphQL**, **gRPC**, **Beam/Flink**, **Protobuf**, **Kafka**, express.js, MongoDB/SQL, Next.js, SSR, SEO, JWT

DevOps: NPM/nexus,
Docker/K8S, TravisCI/Jenkins,
Truffle, AWS CSAA, GNU
make, shell script

Languages: Javascript, **Nodejs**, **Golang**, **Python**, **bash** 

Front-End: html/css/sass, Javascript, **React/Redux**, **MobX**, Gulp, **Webpack**, **RWD** 

### OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

**use-form-react,** a react form hook made building form use in any react app.

**mern,** open sourced mern stack boilerplate repo and with over 1K downloads and clones.

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update and
improve testing environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

## <u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Mateo — *Lead Engineer turned Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

- Co-authored whitepaper, designed and developed the end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month. Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Developed an ERC-20 compatible VentureCoin(VCN) token and successfully launched a 3-month crowd-sale in November 2017.

#### **Yeah Education Group,** Berkeley — Lead Engineer Dec. 2015 - April 2017

 Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API. Successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

### <u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Web Developer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned a full satisfaction rate from clients.

#### **EDUCATION**

## <u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental). Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

## <u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Entrepreneur* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Grown <u>venode</u> project into <u>BNS</u> and graduated as top 3 of "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day. Completed full Hero Training Program and was nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper.

#### **HACKATHONS/AWARDS**

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - 1st place of Uber Challenge for building Teleport, an advertisement site that connects customers and business.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall**[2015] for building

Connect, a radio player

controlled with Myo gesture

controller.

#### MENTORSHIP/BLOG

#### **Distributed Tech Salon**

authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web dev, smart contract, DevOps and Arc. design topics.

<u>Group</u> on Github I founded virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor

**Reactathon, 2017** Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization